<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CaPeesh Consulting LLC Video Blog with Charletta Wilson</title>
    <description>Our mission is to be the best resource for whole-person leadership development. Whether you are a small or family-owned business, government or corporate leader, our team can answer any questions you might have around leading with heart.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 15:42:29 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 15:42:29 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Choosing What’s Right Over Our Own Comfort</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_QYf3S9o3eM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bravery is not the absence of fear. It is choosing to do what’s right over our one’s comfort. Courage requires skill that begins with understanding what it means to be vulnerable. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like many, I’m deeply saddened yet energized by our nation’s current state of unrest. The compounding effect of the COVID-19 pandemic and the tipping point of systemic oppression have come to a head.  BUT change is making its way. No one is immune to the tensions, discomfort, and collective pain that change brings. However, &lt;strong&gt;in these shifts, and in the complexity of these times, leaders at every level can take part in building brave workspaces. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does this look like? Senior leaders, your folks need to hear from you. At the very least, be willing to listen and listen deeply. Remaining silent and pretending that the elephant isn’t in the room doesn’t create peace or trust. If anything, choosing neutrality and being silent sends an apathetic message, which is much louder than words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Senior leaders—your folks need to hear from you.%20http://localhost:4000/choosing-whats-right-over-our-own-comfort.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Senior leaders—your folks need to hear from you.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my research on millennials’ work perceptions, one theme was made clear.  Among top considerations of one’s intent to remain with an employer, the millennial worker wants to know his/her employer cares about them at the person-level AND the world at large. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taking time to listen and creating space for people to be seen and heard is the best form of social responsibility leaders can provide right now.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t worry—if you haven’t taken this step yet, it’s not too late. If your conversations come from an honest place, laced with curiosity, a simple question, such as, “What are you experiencing?” can be an open-door for insight and building trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Systemic reform is a long game. It will take a heck of a lot of honest conversations, but we need skill to do this. The problem I’m seeing is that a lot of leaders buy into &lt;em&gt;truth over harmony&lt;/em&gt;.  But in fact, this approach is often a contradiction of integrity. We need to be able to speak up and have honest conversations about race and equality. Here’s the catch: Before we ask others to be vulnerable, we need to model this first. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TAKING ACTION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conditions will likely get crazier before they get better.  But here are three actions you’ll want to take now:  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Start investing in brave work for your people.&lt;/strong&gt; We need to go beyond just book reading and dropping definitions. We need to dig deep and do our own work. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Listen and create space for people to be seen and heard.&lt;/strong&gt; This is where we build bridges and how relationships are made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. You don’t have to do this perfectly, but you have to do &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; Your actions give others hope and permission to navigate the way forward. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If any of these concepts strike a cord or you want to learn more about how to grow brave skills within your team, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. Aloha, and be well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 16:24:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/choosing-whats-right-over-our-own-comfort.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/choosing-whats-right-over-our-own-comfort.html</guid>
        
        <category>Coaching</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Leaders Need a Coach</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZzBnte4Ok90?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aloha! I hope this message finds you and your loved ones healthy and safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lately, I’ve been coaching clients through some common themes, and one of them is &lt;strong&gt;inner dialogue&lt;/strong&gt;. I truly believe that our inner dialogue can get us into a lot of trouble and cause us to miscommunicate. You need to think about the &lt;strong&gt;assumptions&lt;/strong&gt; you have when beginning conversations. I won’t mention the familiar adage about assumptions, but you likely know what I mean. If you can identify that an assumption is creeping in your thought process, it’s helpful to ask yourself what information might I be missing?  Questions invoke spaciousness for more discovery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Questions invoke spaciousness for more discovery.%20http://localhost:4000/why-leaders-need-a-coach.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Questions invoke spaciousness for more discovery.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re in decision-making mode and find you’re thinking about &lt;strong&gt;worst-case scenarios&lt;/strong&gt; with negative outcomes, listen for this in your thoughts. Disrupt these thoughts with appreciative inquiry: ‘Yes, this &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; occur, but &lt;strong&gt;what opportunities are presented here?&lt;/strong&gt; It’s all about mindset; move from a fixed to a growth mindset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all have an &lt;strong&gt;inner critic&lt;/strong&gt;, and some may call it their saboteur or enemy. I named my inner critic, Nelly. She often cautions me to avoid trying new things or taking risks.  Whatever you call it, recognize that the inner voice that tries to keep us small is just trying to protect us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I love about coaching is that I get to help leaders grow in their awareness and capacity to put these potential derailers in check, and provide them with tools and practices to apply, especially when tensions are high. &lt;strong&gt;As leaders grow into their skills to be coached, they also grow in their skills to coach others.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions or would like to learn more about how you can become a great leader through coaching, contact me via phone or email me at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:info@capeeshconsulting.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;info@capeeshconsulting.com&lt;/a&gt;. I would love to help you. Aloha!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 14:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-leaders-need-a-coach.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-leaders-need-a-coach.html</guid>
        
        <category>Coaching</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Boosting Your Resilience</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/eiNf27am3Yo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you boost resilience within your work team?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Begin with self. Resilience is our ability to recover from setback, failure, and disruption. It’s not an event— it’s a journey, and we get to do it over and over again. Unfortunately, there’s no pill for resilience. It’s more like a group of muscles that we practice repeatedly: The more you use them, the stronger they get. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are three steps to implement in your workplace:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Acknowledge and name it.&lt;/strong&gt; When we acknowledge and name where we’ve fallen short or where the pain point is, we loosen the power and grip it has over our life. Naming what we’re experiencing and identifying the emotion that goes along with it will help boost recovery. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The more we practice, the better we get—and the stronger we are.%20http://localhost:4000/boosting-your-resilience.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The more we practice, the better we get—and the stronger we are.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Give yourself permission to be human and make mistakes.&lt;/strong&gt; This step is tricky because, if you’re like me and grew up believing you had to be perfect (or at least look perfect on the outside), you know perfection is far from reality. When I’ve had a fall and have been able to identify that it hurts, I ask myself, “What would you tell your 5-year-old self if she had a similar experience?” By incorporating this practice, I’m growing my self-compassion and self-empathy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Refrain from blame language.&lt;/strong&gt; If you get stuck in a rut, cast blame, or find fault in what happened and aren’t able to move on, you’re wasting energy. Reframe the situation from “What’s happened?” to “Where’s the opportunity?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more we practice, the better we get—and the stronger we are. That’s how we empower our team members. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to learn more about boosting resilience, don’t hesitate to send me an email. I’m here to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 13:41:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/boosting-your-resilience.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/boosting-your-resilience.html</guid>
        
        <category>Coaching</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Importance of Boosting Psychological Safety</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/KkPeDnDf-p4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clients and prospects frequently ask me about what they can do to get their employees through the COVID-19 crisis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer: Focus on psychological safety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Harvard Business School’s, Dr. Amy Edmonson, psychological safety is the feeling or sense that you won’t be humiliated or punished if you speak up, ask questions, or share concerns. Right now, we need that feeling more than ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, a friend shared a post on social media that said something we’ve been hearing more and more these days: “We’re all in this together.” &lt;strong&gt;The truth is that we are all facing the same storm, but we’re also all in different boats.&lt;/strong&gt; As leaders, we can set the stage by being vulnerable and acknowledging that we are indeed going through uncertain times. When an employee has a concern, humble listening is the best approach. Listen for intent and be empathetic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Psychological safety is something we can access right away to help our employees get to the other side of this struggle.%20http://localhost:4000/the-importance-of-boosting-psychological-safety.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Psychological safety is something we can access right away to help our employees get to the other side of this struggle.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To build on psychological safety, &lt;strong&gt;we can offer clear communication and multiple avenues for access.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter what’s going on, we must &lt;strong&gt;focus on destigmatizing failure&lt;/strong&gt; and keeping the bigger picture in mind. The bigger picture, in the case of the pandemic, is that we’re all in this together and we’re going to get to the other side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Psychological safety is something we can access right away to help our employees get to the other side of this struggle. Not only does it create shared meaning of the experience we’re currently in, but it also boosts our confidence that we can work together as a team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or would like further information, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 15:12:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-importance-of-boosting-psychological-safety.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-importance-of-boosting-psychological-safety.html</guid>
        
        <category>Coaching</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome To My Blog</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Aloha — &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than ever, we need &lt;strong&gt;relevant guidance&lt;/strong&gt; on how to navigate the dynamics of our rapidly changing world.&lt;strong&gt; I want to keep you better updated through RELEVANT, PRACTICAL, and FREE content.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m an industrial and organizational psychologist, certified mindfulness coach, certified Dare to Lead™ facilitator and educator of leadership.  I’ve worked with hundreds of leaders to grow &lt;strong&gt;effective leadership&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;brave teams,&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;profitable businesses.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m working every day to help my clients and serve their needs. I know how to guide business leaders and help them grow their capacity for courage, compassion, and creativity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I’ll be posting two monthly video messages on this blog to keep you updated. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They will be valuable and useful content to help you stay on top of what’s happening in the business leadership world. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m committed to providing steady guidance to help you and your team move forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to know how CaPeesh can help you and your teams thrive, &lt;a href=&quot;https://capeeshconsulting.com/contact/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;set up a consultation call with me&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and let’s explore if we’d be a good fit together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check back because content will be coming soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 14:57:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-my-blog.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-my-blog.html</guid>
        
        <category>Coaching</category>
        
        <category>Events</category>
        
        <category>Consulting</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
